emetrix.com 2006-12-30

# Privacy

**EMETRIX PRIVACY STATEMENT**

**The Way We Put It Together Is What Sets Us Apart**

Emetrix and its subsidiaries and affiliated companies respect the privacy of our partners and suppliers of products or services, clients and their customers. The purpose of this privacy statement is to provide you with information concerning our services, the types of information we are provided or obtain ourselves through visits to or use of our Website, how we use that information, whether we disclose the information provided to us to others and the options you have with regard to the use of and correction of that information. Our goal in handling information provided to us in connection with the processing of transactions on our Website is to comply with applicable data privacy laws and to offer users of our Website notice, choice, consent, security, data integrity, access and enforcement with regard to personal information provided to us by individuals in conjunction with those transactions. 

**What Information Do We Collect, How Do We Use It?**

Emetrix provides its partners and suppliers with a variety of fulfillment, support and E-commerce related services. Some of these services may be provided through sites bearing our partners and suppliers names and trademarks.

Depending on the nature of the services provided by Emetrix to our partners or suppliers, Emetrix may receive personal information either from you directly or from our partner or supplier who provides us with the personal information to fulfill a service to you on their behalf. In some circumstances personal information that Emetrix receives from you directly may be provided to our partners or suppliers in order for them to fulfill a service to us for your benefit or directly to you. The personal information may include but is not limited to your name, mailing address, phone number, type of hardware or software you own and other information required to provide you with the product, service or support requested. 

Emetrix also employs other companies to provide services to it in connection with your transaction. We may use companies to process credit card payments, deliver packages, send mail, analyze data, provide marketing aid and assistance, provide customer service, and otherwise provide services to us to enable us to serve you and enhance our services. These organizations may have access to personal information as required to permit them to perform their obligations to us. We require these organizations to undertake to protect personal information and to only use it in accordance with applicable laws and for the purposes for which they are specifically engaged. 

Some of the ways in which we will use the personal information provided us include:

a) to take, process or deliver your order, process or obtain payment or notify you of the status of your order;

b) in connection with keys, access codes or other information as may be required to permit you to access our partners’ sites to receive products, updates or services;

c) to provide it to industry and credit related organizations for security, credit or fraud prevention purposes;

d) to register your purchase with the manufacturer or service provider for warranty, technical support or similar purposes;

e) to facilitate the renewal of subscriptions for products or services; 

f) to provide you with technical support; 

g) to monitor service or purchasing patterns;

h) to provide you with service updates, announcements, and other product offerings;

i) to send you, with your consent, newsletters or promotional emails or undertake other promotional activities; and

j) to permit you to participate in online surveys and polls, assuming you voluntarily agree to provide such information in connection with these surveys and polls. 

We may also provide links from our Website to third party websites who may provide services to you directly or on our behalf. THE PRIVACY POLICIES OF THESE THIRD PARTY SITES MAY BE DIFFERENT FROM OUR PRIVACY POLICIES AND WILL GOVERN ANY TRANSACTIONS UNDERTAKEN ON THAT SITE. We urge you to review the privacy policy of any site to which you are linked. 

The information we receive may be transferred outside the European Union for processing. We will undertake to obligate any person or entity receiving such information to process any such information in accordance with this Privacy Statement and in accordance with applicable law. By submitting your order either to our partner or to us you consent to the use of your personal information as set forth above and the transfer of that data as outlined in this paragraph to our partners or those individuals or entities we engage to provide services in connection with your transaction. 

**Will Emetrix Give Me Notice of Requests for My Information made By Law Enforcement or Governmental Agencies?**

No. Emetrix may be required to respond to subpoenas, court orders or be asked to respond to other legitimate requests for your personal information from appropriate law enforcement or governmental authorities. In such situations, we will release personally identifiable information to third parties and organizations when we believe it is appropriate for us to do so in order to comply with the law or to protect against fraud. We will also release such information:

(a) to cooperate with law enforcement or other governmental investigations (without necessarily requiring the law enforcement or government agency requesting the information to formally serve us with a subpoena), 

(b) to comply with all valid court orders or subpoenas, 

(c) to protect our legal rights and those of our users; and/or 

(d) when we believe it is needed for fraud protection and/or credit risk reduction. 

Emetrix also reserves the right to report to such entities any activities that we believe to be unlawful. Any report made to under this paragraph will be made without prior notice to you. 

In the event Emetrix merges with another entity, is acquired by another entity, or enters into a business combination with another entity, Emetrix may be required to disclose and some or all of your personally identifiable information to that entity to continue serving you. 

**Children’s Privacy**

Emetrix will comply with applicable laws and regulations relating to collection and use of information from children, including the Children’s On-line Privacy Protection Act of the United States. We will follow the notice, consent and opt-out procedures of that legislation and will establish reasonable procedures designed to protect information collected from children. 

**How Does Emetrix Protect Customer Information?**

Customers who buy through the Emetrix system are shopping on a secure server which encrypts all of a customer’s personal information. This makes it difficult, if not impossible, for a third party to access or use your personal information in an unauthorized manner. 

Emetrix has developed its service with security as a top priority. We use firewalls to prevent access to information in our system and Secure Socket Layers (“SSL”) to encrypt your personal information and protect it from disclosure, destruction, modification or use. 

**What About Cookies?**

"Cookies" are a data analysis technique that uses information stored on your browser. Emetrix’s cookies are used to identify a customer, not to identify specific customer traits. If you do not want cookies in your browser, you may set your browser to reject cookies or to notify you when a website attempts to place a cookie in your browser. 

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information**

We may also collect other information which does not in and of itself identify a specific individual. This information includes IP addresses, search terms, domain names and browser types. We use this information to track usage and other patterns on our Websites. 

**Information Sharing**

Emetrix does not sell, trade or rent personal information to anyone. We will not use or share your personally identifiable information with others except those individuals or entities which we have engaged to provide services to you, for those purposes set forth above or with your consent. 

**Your Choices**

Emetrix will not share or use your personal information in ways unrelated to the purpose for which you provided us the information, without providing you the opportunity to consent to such unrelated uses. At the time you provide your information, we will offer you a choice as to whether or not you wish to receive further communications about special offers, product information or other marketing messages. We may provide this information to our business partners and suppliers. If you choose not to receive these communications, we will not use your personally identifiable information for this purpose. 

**Accuracy and Access**

Emetrix will provide you with the ability to access your personal information maintained on our system and permit you to review and correct that personal information or change your choices or preferences with regard to that personal information; for instance, whether or not you wish to be contacted about specials or new products. We reserve the right to protect our own or other’s confidential or personal information in connection with your review and correction and further reserve the right to charge you a reasonable fee for access to your personal information dependent on the nature and scope of your request and the difficulty in complying with your request. 

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

Emetrix may amend this Policy from time-to-time. We suggest you visit this Website periodically to determine whether or not any such changes have been made. 

**Emetrix Contact Information**

If you have questions or comments or would like to contact us concerning our Privacy Statement, please contact us online at the address at the bottom of this page.

If you feel your inquiry or request has not been handled to your satisfaction, please contact Emetrix’s Privacy Department at the number listed at the bottom of this page.
